usabilla.com 2019-12-19

# Usabilla Privacy Statement

To increase transparency and ease of access, from 1 January, 2020 the [SurveyMonkey privacy policy](https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/legal/privacy-policy/) will apply to our Usabilla customers (new and existing) and we will be sun-setting the Usabilla privacy notice. This does not change how we handle your personal information. 

Beginning January 1, 2020, for our users who are California residents, we included certain disclosures in connection with the California Consumer Privacy Act ([See here](https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/legal/region-specific-privacy-statement/)). 

We’ve added a [new online form](https://help.surveymonkey.com/contact?form=GDPR) making it even easier for our users to submit a personal data rights request. 

This privacy statement concerns the processing of personal data by usabilla.com, support.usabilla.com, jobs.usabilla.com, developers.usabilla.com, academy.usabilla.com, and go.usabilla.com (“Public Websites”). It does not address the processing of personal data by Usabilla's products (Usabilla for Websites, Usabilla for Apps, Usabilla for Email), which is addressed in our Terms and Conditions.

From 06 August 2019, any new customers with Usabilla will operate under this privacy statement and the [SurveyMonkey privacy policy](https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/legal/privacy-policy/) (which is incorporated by reference into this privacy statement from this date). Where there is a conflict between the SurveyMonkey privacy policy and this privacy statement, this privacy statement takes precedence. This change does not impact Usabilla customers with active agreements dated prior to the date of this change.

The Public Websites are owned and operated by Usabilla BV. Usabilla is responsible for processing personal data in accordance with the Dutch Data Protection Act and General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

Our contact information is:

Usabilla BV  
Rokin 16  
1012 KR Amsterdam  
The Netherlands  
Tel: +31 (0) 20 772 78 35  
Email: support@usabilla.com

On our Public Websites, we do not collect personal data, unless you provide your personal data through a contact form, request a product demo, subscribe to the newsletter, leave feedback through the feedback button, sign up on our partner page, or fill in a survey. In those cases, we only collect general contact information, such as your name, email address and/or phone number, sometimes optionally. 

Our Public Websites use cookies. In some cases, the use of cookies is considered equivalent to the processing of personal data. Personal data collected by the cookies on our website is mainly used for analytical purposes. For more information about our use of cookies, please refer to our Cookie Policy.

Personal data collected on the Public Websites is only used for the purposes for which it was provided. The following is a complete list of our Public Websites’ purposes of data collection: 

  * We will only use your personal data to contact you for a demo if that is why you have provided the personal data. 

  * If you make use of our contact form, we will only use the provided data to contact you to answer your question. 

  * If you subscribe to the newsletter, we will only use the collected email address in order to send you the newsletter until you unsubscribe from this service. 

  * If you leave feedback on our website, we will only use the optionally provided email address to potentially contact you about this feedback. 

  * If you consume one of our most recent e-books or webinars, we use the provided email address if and only if we believe there is a potential business opportunity, in which case our sales team might get in contact. 

  * If you apply for a job at Usabilla, we will only use your contact details provided for recruitment proposes. 

  * 

We will retain collected personal data for as long as is necessary to provide you with the requested service, unless a longer retention period is required by law. 

We take adequate measures to protect your data from being stolen, lost, or used in any way that is not in line with the purposes for which the data was collected. 

We do not sell your personal data to third parties. 

We will not give your personal data to third parties, unless we are obligated by law, for example in case of a lawful request by law enforcement authorities. 

We may transfer personal data to other companies within the Usabilla group of companies, typically our sales and support offices. We apply the same data protection measures in all our offices. 

We may use third parties to process personal data for certain services. For example, our Request a Demo page and the sending of newsletters is hosted by HubSpot. If you receive emails from us, we may use certain analytics tools to capture data such as when you open our email or click on any links or banners our email contains. We ensure that all third parties provide an adequate level of protection for your personal data. We only share information with them that is required for the services offered. 

We may occasionally send you promotional communications about product or feature updates, events, webinars, newsletters, content resources, offers, contests or provide you with other news or information about us and our select partners. Except for cases where we are required to do so by law (e.g. notifying you of a data breach), you have the opportunity to unsubscribe from receiving these messages by using the unsubscribe link within each email, or emailing us ([privacy@usabilla.com](mailto:privacy@usabilla.com)) to have your contact information removed from our promotional email list or registration database. 

You have the right to correct, update, amend, or completely remove your personal data from our database. You can also ask for a structured and machine-readable record of the personal data you provided to us. You can file a request to access the data that is processed through the Public Websites by sending an email to [privacy@usabilla.com](mailto:privacy@usabilla.com). In order to verify your identity, we ask that you send a copy of your ID attached to your request. Be sure to blacken out your photograph and personal identity number or social security number. Following your access request, you can request rectification or removal. 

The Public Websites are fully compliant to the recent privacy developments according to the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), and our efforts towards achieving this can be found on our GDPR page. 

If you wish to raise a complaint on how we have handled your personal data, you can contact us at [privacy@usabilla.com](mailto:privacy@usabilla.com) and we will investigate the matter. If you are not satisfied with our response or believe we are processing your personal data not in accordance with the law, you can file a complaint with the Dutch Data Protection Authority (Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens). 

This privacy statement was created in May 2017 and edited on November 21st, 2019. When we change the policy on how collected data on this website is treated, we will announce this through an alteration of our privacy statement.
